John B. Sheerin Papers
John B. Sheerin Papers
1948-1971
Sheerin, John B.
1.5 linear ft.
Printed material and writings of John B. Sheerin, Roman Catholic editor, columnist and pioneer in interfaith relations.
2707532
Biographical History
Reverend John B. Sheerin (1907?-1992) was a Roman Catholic editor, columnist and pioneer in interfaith relations. A graduate of Fordham University (BA, 1928; JD, 1930), he was editor of The Catholic World, a monthly journal published by the Paulist Fathers, from 1948-1972. He was an outspoken opponent of the Vietnam War and a supporter of civil rights. [Adapted from his obituary in the New York Times, 15 Jan 1992.]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The John B. Sheerin Papers consists of printed material and writings, much of it editorials from Sheerin's work as editor of The Catholic World, including some indexes to the editorials.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
has a number of collections relating to church and clergy. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Sheerin, John B.; Catholic World.; Catholic Church -- Clergy -- Political activity -- United States.; Catholics -- United States -- Intellectual life.; Catholics -- United States -- Periodicals.; Catholics -- United States -- Political activity; Editorials.; Indexes (reference sources); Photographs.; Printed materials (object genre); Periodical editors.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of John B. Sheerin, 1970-1971.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Photo, biographical sketch, 1970 (Box 1)
- Writings
  - Articles, various publications, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
  - Book, Human Life in Our Day, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Editorials
    - Index covering 1948-1971 (Box 1)
    - Editorials in "Catholic World", 1948-1971; 8 folders (Box 1)
  - "Sum and Substance" column
    - Index covering 1956-1968 (Box 2)
    - "Sum and Substance" column, 1956-1963; 8 folders (Box 2)
    - "Sum and Substance" column, 1964-1970; 7 folders (Box 3)